[Breakfast should be a raw egg on hot rice. It tastes so good with a little soy sauce drizzled on top.]
[Today, "Tama-chan" appears. She was given that name by Kagura, who loves eggs.]
＜ｺﾞﾐ… ひと口に ｺﾞﾐといっても
さまざまなものがある｡
Trash... It is a single word, but there are many different types.
A woman with a cane came to throw away a single bag.
松葉杖の女が捨てに来たのは
一つの袋だった｡
A smelly bag that oozed blood.
生臭い においを放つ 血の滴る袋｡
妙だと思ったが
清掃員は 中を改めずに➡
The trash collector thought it strange, but did not check its contents
and threw it into his truck.
ｺﾞﾐを収集車に放り込んだ｡
なぜなら その女は➡
The woman stared at him with eerie vacant eyes watching as he threw away the bag.
袋を捨てるまで 清掃員を
じっと見つめていたから｡
何より 女の異様な風体が
それをためらわせた｡
More than anything, the woman's bizarre appearance made him nervous.
夏場にも かかわらず
肌を少しも見せない厚着｡
It was summer, yet she wore heavy clothing that did not show any of her skin.
Her hands that were just barely exposed were tightly wrapped in bandages.
そこから かすかにのぞく肢体は
痛々しく包帯に包まれていた｡
The following day, the woman came again, carrying a smelly bag.
翌日 女は また来た｡
生臭い袋を持って｡
And the next, and the day after that, the woman came with a bag,
明くる日も 明くる日も
女は袋を持ってきては➡
日増しに衰える体を引きずり
じっと こちらを見ていた｡
dragging her body which grew weaker by the day; staring at the trash collector.
ある日 女は来なかった｡
One day, the woman did not come.
but the usual smelly bag was on top of the trash pile.
代わりに いつもの生臭い袋が
ｺﾞﾐの山に一つ｡
The woman's stare was not here.
いつもの女の視線はない｡
清掃員が袋の中を覗いてみた｡
The trash collector peeked inside the bag.
女は じっと
こちらを見つめていた｡
The woman stared at him...just as she always had.
いつものように…＞
(清掃員)ちょっと ﾀﾞﾒですよ！
今日は 資源ｺﾞﾐの日！
This isn't right. Today is recyclable trash day.
You're combustible trash!
あなたは燃えるｺﾞﾐでしょ｡
(女)すみません…｡
I'm sorry...
Let's sort our trash!
[Let's sort our trash!]
If you don't, I might haunt you.
守らないと 私 出ちゃうかも…｡
You call that a commercial? What bad taste!
(銀時)ＣＭかよ！
趣味の悪いもん作りやがって…！
They have to resort to such threats because no one follows the trash schedule.
誰も ｺﾞﾐの日 守らねえから
脅しに回りやがった！
あ？ 明日
燃えないｺﾞﾐの日だったか…｡
Oh...
Tomorrow is non-combustible trash day...
I put out the JUMP...
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣出してきちまった…｡
まぁ いっか！
No harm.
I might haunt you.
((出ちゃうかも…))
ﾊﾞｶ言ってんじゃねえよ！
ｶﾞｷじゃあるまいし！
Don't be ridiculous. We're not kids here.
明日 取りに行きゃ いいだろ｡
I can go and get it tomorrow.
Geez...
(神楽)もう… 何ｱﾙか？
こんな遅くに…｡
What do you want at this hour?
いや 違うんだよ｡
あの あれｺﾞﾐがよ 気になってよ…｡
Nothing, it's just the trash...
I'm worried about it.
なんで私が
つきあわなきゃいけないｱﾙ？
Why do I have to go with you? Staying up late is terrible for my complexion.
夜更かしは 美容の大敵ｱﾙ！
Don't you realize that?
そのへん わかってんのか？
ﾊﾞｯｶ！ ｵﾒｴ 違うよ？
Silly, you misunderstand. It's not that I'm scared or anything.
怖いとか そういうんじゃないよ｡
言っとくけど あれだよ！
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣に交ぜて➡
Just so you know, I threw away your favorite magazine with the JUMP.
お前の お気に入りの雑誌
捨てちゃって…｡
Seriously? My Lady's Eight, with the evil daughter-in-law special article?
[Note: Spoof on the magazine "Jyosei Seven."]
ﾏｼﾞでか!? 『女性ｴｲﾄ』ｱﾙか？
鬼嫁特集ｱﾙか!?
ちょっと あれ取ってくんの
手伝えよ！
Help me retrieve it.
ｲﾔｱﾙ 臭いｱﾙ…｡
No, something stinks.
Okay, you don't have to help me. Just stay by me.
じゃあ 手伝わなくていいから
ｵﾚのそばにいろよ｡
No, something stinks.
ｲﾔｱﾙ 臭いｱﾙ｡
いい加減にしろよ！
Cut it out! Stop being so selfish!
わがままばっかり言いやがって！
I came to you because I was trying to help you!
ｵﾚは お前のためを思って
こうして来てんだよ!?
Forget it! I get it! I won't ask you! Suit yourself!
もういいよ！ わかったよ！
お前には頼まねえ！ 好きにしろ!!
Just stand quietly and watch!
そこで黙って見てるがいいわ！
Don't go anywhere. Just stay and watch me!
どこにも行かず
じっと見守ってくれるがいいわ！
ｲﾔｱﾙ｡ もう眠いから帰るｱﾙ｡
I don't want to. I'm sleepy, so I'm going home.
神楽ちゃ～ん！ ごめんなさい！
もういいから！
Kagura-chan!
I'm sorry!
All you have to do is sing the "Doraemon" song right here!
そこで 『ﾄﾞﾗえもん』の歌
歌ってくれるだけでいいから!!
♪♪(神楽)｢ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙﾙ ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙﾙ ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙｰ｣
What?!
あれ？ なんか どっかから
聞いたようなﾃｰﾏ曲が➡
Sounds like a theme song I've heard somewhere before.
[Note: Spoof of theme song for the mystery show "Yo ni mo kimyo na monogatari" -Tales of the Unusual.]
聞こえてくるよ！
神楽ちゃんだよね？
That is you, isn't it, Kagura-chan? That is you, right?!
これ神楽ちゃんだよね？
Dammit!! I'm not giving in!
ｺﾝﾁｷｼｮｰ！ 負けてたまるか!!
Ran ran ra ra ran ran ran.
[Note: He's singing an off-beat version of the Nausicaa of the Valley of the Wind song.]
♪♪｢ﾗｰﾗﾗ ﾗﾗﾗｰﾗ｣
(親父)おい うるせぇよ！
今 何時だと思ってんだ!?
Hey! Keep it down! Do you know what time it is?!
すみません おじさん！
おじさん 悪いけど➡
I'm sorry, mister!
Mister, would you mind watching me? From there?
ｵﾚのこと見ててもらえる？
そこで見てて！
なに気持わりぃこと言ってんだ！
警察 呼ぶぞ！
What? What a creepy thing to ask! I'll call the police!
Please, really!
ぜひ お願いします！
｢お願いします｣じゃねえよ！
Don't even ask!
Okay, got it!
よし 取った～!!
(神楽)｢ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙﾙ ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙﾙ｣
Hey, you're being rude, Kagura. You're disturbing the neighborhood!
おい！ しつけぇんだよ
神楽 ﾃﾒｴ！
ご近所の迷惑も考えろ！
Mister, watch me until I'm done.
おい おじさん！
最後まで見ててくれよ！
(芙蓉)了解｡
Roger.
Target... acquired.
(芙蓉)目標 補足しました｡
解析ﾓｰﾄﾞに移行します｡
Switching to analysis mode.
Blood pressure, heart rate both rising...
(芙蓉)血圧 心拍ともに上昇…｡
目標 喪失しました｡
Target has lost consciousness.
["Please Help by Separating Your Trash"]
♪♪(神楽)｢ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙﾙ ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙﾙ ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙｰ｣
♪♪｢ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙﾙ ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙﾙ ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙｰ｣
♪♪｢ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙﾙ｣
What the hell are you doing?
何してんだ ﾃﾒｴ!?
Good morning.
[Note: Spoof of Cozy Tomita who is an impersonator for Tamori, who is the host of "Yo ni mo kimyo na monogatari" -Tales of the Unusual.]
おはようございます｡ 髪切った？
Did you cut your hair?
No, I haven't! What sort of mean prank is this while I'm asleep?!
切ってねえよ！ なに寝込みに
悪質なｲﾔｶﾞﾗｾしてんだ ﾃﾒｴは！
Geez!
ったく どうりで
ｲﾔな夢みるはずだぜ｡
No wonder I have such terrible dreams.
Let's eat.
ほうほう どんな？
What kind of dreams?
生首がよぉ… まぁ いいや！
A dismembered head...
Never mind. They say never to talk about the dreams you see while sleeping or awake.
寝てみる夢も 起きてみる夢も
人に話すこっちゃねえってな！
I'd only be a laughingstock.
笑われるのがｵﾁよ｡
ｺﾞﾐ捨て場に生首ｱﾙか？
A dismembered head at the trash disposal area?
お前 なんで!?
うなされてたよ｡
How did you...?
You were having a nightmare. You're too old to be having nightmares like a little kid.
いい歳こいて
わんぱく小僧みたいな➡
夢みるｱﾙな｡
新八に言うなよ ｺﾗ！
Don't tell Shinpachi, okay? I'll give you 300 yen.
300円あげるから…｡
I don't remember what I did before I went to sleep. What was I doing yesterday?
寝る前の記憶が ねえんだが
ｵﾚ 昨日 何してた？
You went to the trash disposal area to get your JUMP.
ｺﾞﾐ捨て場に
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣取りに行ってたｱﾙ｡
しばらくしても帰ってこないから
見に行ったら➡
You didn't come back, so I went to check and found you asleep in the disposal area.
ｺﾞﾐ捨て場で寝てたよ｡
神楽ちゃん 神楽ちゃん？
(卵を割る音)
Kagura-chan... Kagura-chan...
What is that?
っていうか 何それ？
卵割り器！ 昨日 見つけたｱﾙ！
An egg cracker! I found it yesterday.
No, no, no, no, no. Nooooo!
いやいやいやいや いやぁ～!!
That's no egg cracker! It's that dismembered head from yesterday!
卵割り器 違う!!
生首それ 昨日の！
Y-You! I wasn't dreaming! Why did you take that thing, you dummy?!
おっ… お前！ 夢どころか
なんで ﾃｲｸｱｳﾄしてんだ ﾊﾞｶﾔﾛｳ!!
It's not a dismembered head. It's an egg cracker.
生首違う！ 卵割り器ｱﾙ！
What are you talking about, kid?! What do you mean, an egg cracker?!
さっきから何言ってんの この子！
卵割り器って何だよ!?
ねえよ そんな器物!!
There's not such thing!
Eggs are something you want to crack over someone's head.
卵というもの つい人の頭で
割ってしまいたくなるものよ｡
But that would be rude. So now I have this!
でも それじゃ迷惑｡
でも これさえあれば！
とぉ！
違う！ 絶対違う!!
No! Absolutely not!
Hey! What's with this scene!
おい！ 何だ この絵面！
It's not something you want to see in the evening!
夕方にあっていい
絵面じゃねえよ!!
Go and put it back! Put it back where it was!
早く戻してこい！
元あったところに戻してこい！
No! That's my egg cracker! I'm not letting you have it!
ｲﾔｱﾙ！ あれは 私の卵割り器ｱﾙ！
絶対 渡さないね！
ふざけんな！ あんなもん
ご近所の方に見られたら…｡
That's enough! If anyone around here sees that thing...!
(定春)ﾊｯﾊｯ ﾊｯﾊｯ！
(衝撃音)
Sadaharu, please don't do that.
定春… それは 勘弁してくれ！
それは ｵﾓﾁｬじゃないからな！
こっちよこしなさい！
That's not a toy. Okay? Let me have it. I'll give you beef jerky.
ﾋﾞｰﾌｼﾞｬｰｷｰあげるから！
定春！ それ 私の卵割り器ｱﾙよ！
Sadaharu! That's my egg cracker!
I told you, that's not an egg cracker!
卵割り器じゃねえって
言ってんだろ!!
Give it up! I'll be your egg cracker from tomorrow on, so give it up!
あきらめろ！
明日から ｵﾚが お前の➡
卵割り器になってやるから
あきらめろ！
Was that a new pickup line?
何だ これ…
新しい口説き文句か!?
うわっ！
うほぉ～!?
Forget it! Don't say I didn't tell you!
もう知らねえ！
ｵﾚ もう知らねえ！
Sh-Shinpachi! Don't touch it! You'll leave your prints on it!
し… 新八！ 触るな！
指紋がつく！ 証拠を残すな！
Don't leave any evidence behind! Get rid of it quickly!
早く処分しろ～!!
Isn't this Etsuko-chan?
(新八)これ 悦子ちゃん？
Etsuko-chan?! Someone you know named Etsuko-chan?!
悦子ちゃ～ん!?
お前の知り合いの悦子ちゃんか!?
No.
違いますよ！
これ 今 人気の からくり家政婦➡
This is Etsuko-chan, the robot maid that's popular these days.
悦子ちゃんですよ！
からくり!?
Robot?
違うね！ 卵割り器ｱﾙ！
You're wrong! It's an egg cracker!
[Robot Shop]
炊事 洗濯に始まり
事務まで こなす➡
The dream mechanical doll that cooks, does the laundry and can even take care of office work.
夢の からくり人形…｡
Hey, this is awesome.
おい すげぇな！
姑ﾊﾞｰｼﾞｮﾝ ﾂﾝﾃﾞﾚﾊﾞｰｼﾞｮﾝも あんぞ｡
There's a mother-in-law version and even a Tsundere version.
[Note: Tsundere = a conceited, spiky, combative personality that suddenly becomes modest and loving.]
はぁ～ 時代は
ここまで進んでいたとはねぇ…｡
We've really come a long way...
なんでも言うこと聞くし
よく働くし 人間より使えるって➡
From what I hear, it does what you say, works hard and is more useful than a human.
企業や商人なんかの間で
大人気なんですよ｡
It's extremely popular with businesses and stores.
まぁ 一般人が手を出せる値段じゃ
ないですけど…｡
The price is not something an ordinary person can afford, though.
ちなみに新八… お前
なんで そんなに詳しいんだよ？
So, how do you know so much, Shinpachi?
えっ!? いや ｵﾀｸの間でも
結構 人気ですから…｡
Huh? It's quite popular among otaku, as well.
おいおい この子 完全に
いやらしいこと考えてるよ｡
Hey...this boy's having naughty thoughts. He wants it to do everything he asks.
なんでも言うこと
聞かせるつもりだよ｡
なっ!?
What...?
Seriously gross. Don't talk to me for a while.
ﾏｼﾞ ｷﾓｲｱﾙ｡ しばらく私に
話しかけないで｡
Wh-What?! Do you know about dreams men have of maids?!
なっ… なんだぁ～!!
ｷｻﾏにﾒｲﾄﾞのﾛﾏﾝが わかるかぁ～!!
おい どうだ？ じいさん｡
(源外)かなり派手にやられてるな｡
So, how's it look, old man?
It was quite beat up.
Of course it was. Its head was, after all, dismembered.
そりゃそうだ｡ 首ﾁｮﾝﾊﾟだからな｡
まぁ だが肝心なところは
傷ついちゃいねえようだ｡
But the important parts don't appear to be damaged. I can probably fix it.
なんとか なんだろ｡
But, old man, you can't relax, either.
しかし じいさんよぉ➡
ｱﾝﾀも ｵﾁｵﾁしてられねえな｡
えっ…｡
こんなもんが
市場に出回ってるとは➡
With something like this on the market,
江戸いちばんの からくり技師が
追い抜かれる日も➡
the day won't be long when Edo's number one mechanic is surpassed.
近いんじゃねえの？
何 言ってやがる｡
What're you talking about?
こんな軟弱な からくり
作りやがって！
Making such a wimpy robot... He's still creating poor-quality work.
相変わらず
雑な仕事してやがらぁ…｡
Okay, done! I had to make do with what I had, so it's a bit unbalanced.
(源外)よ～し できた！
ありあわせで作ったから➡
ちと ｱﾝﾊﾞﾗﾝｽだけどな…｡
ちょっとぉぉぉっ！
Just a minute!
With what you had?! The entire body was stolen from someplace else!
ありあわせどころか 体丸々
どっかから 丸ﾊﾟｸﾘしてきたよ！
It'll withstand even a year-long war.
[Note: Spoof of Gundam.]
１年戦争でも
耐えられる代物だぞ！
なんで家政婦が
１年も戦争すんだよ！
Why would a maid battle for a year! Why does a maid need a shield?!
なんで家政婦に ｼｰﾙﾄﾞが必要!?
She can hide behind the shield and see lots of things...like a family's problems.
(源外)ｼｰﾙﾄﾞに隠れて
いろいろ見られんだろうが！
家庭の事情とか…｡
見なくていいんだよ！
She doesn't need to see those things! Leave those to Etsuko Ichihara!
[Spoof of "Kaseifu wa miteita" (Maid saw them all). Etsuko Ichihara plays a maid who sees scandals in the house she works in.]
市原 悦子に任せときゃいいんだ
んなもんはっ!!
せっかく 金になりそう
なんだからよぁ…➡
I thought she'd be good for some cash.
もっといい女に ﾎﾞﾝｯ ｷｭｯ ﾎﾞﾝｯの
ﾅｲｽﾊﾞﾃﾞｨにしてくれねえと➡
I can't sell her unless you give her Bang! Pow! Boom! A nice buxom, hourglass body.
売れねえだろうが！
売るってなんだ!?
What do you mean, sell her?! Etsuko-chan will be my own personal, gentle maid!
悦子ちゃんは ﾎﾞｸ専用の ﾎﾞｸだけに
優しいﾒｲﾄﾞになるんだよっ！
うるっせえんだよっ ﾀﾞﾒｶﾞﾈ!!
Shut up, four-eyes! I'll send you to hell first!
お前は 一足先に
冥土に行ってろ～いっ！
断固 ﾒｲﾄﾞ服で！
卵割り機能 つけるｱﾙ！
She definitely needs a maid's outfit!
Attach an egg cracker! One that also takes out the slimy part!
あのﾆｭﾙﾆｭﾙも
取ってくれるやつ！
(源外)いやぁ ようわからんわ…｡
それは違うだろう ｺﾗｯ！
I don't get it.
That's not right!
(神楽)やんのか ｺﾗｯ！
もう いいから…｡
You wanna fight?
Never mind, just make her into your idea of a nice woman.
Bring it on!
ｱﾝﾀなりに いい女作ってくれ！
(神楽)上等だ ｺﾗｯ！
Dirty specs!
…って ｹﾂﾌﾟﾘﾝに
なっただけだろうがぁっ!!
You just made her bum bigger.
You didn't fix the parts that were basically wrong!
根本的に ﾀﾞﾒなところが
直ってねえんだよ！
何!? このｹﾂに対する こだわり！
What is this thing you have for her bum?!
Women with big bums are good-they have easier deliveries.
(源外)ｹﾂがでかい女はいいぞ！
安産だ｡
ふりぃよ！ 古いんだよ！
女の選考の基準がっ！
That's old! So ancient! Your criteria for choosing a woman are so old!
What don't you like? I had a tough time with this part.
何 気に食わねえんだ？
ここなんて
たいへんだったんだぞ｡
It pours soy sauce.
(源外)醤油出るんだぞ！ これ…｡
I don't care about your consideration for eggs on rice!
卵かけご飯への配慮は
いいんだよ！
Why do you people like egg on rice so much?! Though I like it, too!
[Note: Japanese people often eat rice mixed with raw egg and a little soy sauce drizzled on top.]
みんな どんだけ
卵かけご飯 好きなんだよっ！
ｵﾚも好きだけどね!!
ﾊｧ… 注文の多い連中だな｡
You guys make a lot of demands.
これ以上 なんかするっつったら
予算がなぁ…｡
If you want more done, you'll need to pay me more money.
…つ～か ｵﾒｴら 金あんの!?
Do you guys have the money?
[Strawberry Fields]
捨てられた犬みたいに
なってんですけど…｡
She's like an abandoned puppy.
Can't be helped. We don't have the money.
しかたねえだろ｡
金 ねえんだから…｡
これじゃ 売れねえな！
殺人鬼の気分だ…｡
We can't sell her like this. I feel like a killer.
売れるどころか 体がないんじゃ
家政婦としても使えないｱﾙ…｡
Not only can't we sell her, but without a body, we can't use her as a maid.
でも 源外さんの話じゃ
この からくり…➡
But according to Gengai-san, this robot ...
事務処理能力に
特化したものらしいですよ｡
was specially designed for office tasks.
Her previous owner may have been using her more like a computer rather than as a maid.
前の持ち主も ﾒｲﾄﾞとしてより➡
ﾊﾟｿｺﾝみたいな感じで
使ってたんじゃないっすか？
Where's the on switch?
起動って どこにｽｲｯﾁあんだよ！
もし乳首だったら おしまいだ｡
起動できねえぞ！
If it's her nipples, it's hopeless. We won't be able to boot her up.
Your head is what's hopeless.
ｱﾝﾀの頭が おしまいですよ…｡
ｵｨ～！ 起きろっ!!
あっ！
Hey, wake up!
Ack!
Could it be this mole on her head?
この額のﾎｸﾛかな？
ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙ ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙ ﾄﾞｩﾙﾙﾙ ﾄﾞｩ～ﾝ！
(３人)うわぁぁぁっ!!
ついた！
She turned on?!
Unfortunately, your adventures 1, 2 and 3 have disappeared.
[Note: Spoof of saved file for Dragon Quest game.]
(芙蓉)残念ながら
あなたの冒険の書１➡
冒険の書２ 冒険の書３は
消えました｡
Hey, this isn't good. We hit her too hard-the adventures have disappeared.
おい！ ﾔﾍﾞｴぞ！ 強く叩いたから
冒険の書 全部消えちゃったぞ！
冒険の書って なんですか!?
What are the adventures?
She went adventuring somewhere, no doubt.
(神楽)冒険してたんだよ！
どこかで きっと…｡
もう一度 初めから 冒険の書を
作り直してください｡
Please rebuild the adventures from the beginning. First: A name.
まずは 名前から｡
名前つけろって
言ってますけど…｡
It's asking for a name.
It's a hassle, so just say, "Aaaa."
めんどくせえから ｢ああああ｣で
いいだろ？
ﾀﾞﾒですよ！
That won't do. You'll regret it later if you're lazy.
不精すると後悔しますよ｡
魔王と戦ってるときに➡
Where's the excitement if you say "Aaaa" when you're fighting the evil king.
｢ああああ｣とか
ﾃﾝｼｮﾝ下がるでしょ！
魔王って なんだよ!?
魔王と戦うつもりだよ！
What's an evil king? She intends to fight an evil king.
Okay, then "Tama."
[Note: Tama is short for tamago (egg).]
じゃあ 卵で！
了解！
Roger.
Tama?! How far are you going with this egg thing?!
卵!? どんだけ
卵にこだわってんの!!
いよいよ 野良犬みたいに
なってきたな…｡
That sounds like a stray dog.
みなさん 初めまして｡
私の名前は ﾏﾘｰ･ｱﾝﾄﾜﾈｯﾄ｡
How do you do, everyone. My name is Marie Antoinette.
卵 無視したよ！
ｲﾔだったんだ ｲﾔだったんだよ！
She ignored Tama! She didn't like it! She didn't like it!
Everyone calls me "Mole Beam."
みんなには
ﾎｸﾛﾋﾞｰﾑと呼ばれている｡
She was teased! She was totally teased about the mole on her forehead!
ｲｼﾞﾒられてるよ！ 完全に
額のﾎﾞﾀﾝのことでｲｼﾞﾒられてるよ！
つ～か みんなって 誰だよ!?
Who's "everyone"?
Warriors and martial artists. They're physical, but very gloomy.
[Note: Party member types from Dragon Quest game.]
戦士とか 武闘家ｱﾙよ！
ｱｲﾂら 肉体派のくせに
ﾈｸﾗなんだよ！
The memories make me blue. Shall I save the adventure?
なんか 思い出したら
ﾌﾞﾙｰになってきた…｡
冒険の書をｾｰﾌﾞしますか？
She's trying to end the adventure on her own!
何 勝手に
冒険 終えようとしてるの!?
Wait! This adventure is just beginning!
待て おい！ まだ
冒険 始まったばかりだろうが！
Please write down the restart chant.
(芙蓉)復活の呪文を
ﾒﾓしてください｡
Mogagazuboroso, kusaremagurobaromi.
もががずぼろそ
くされまぐろばろみ｡
今どき ﾊﾟｽﾜｰﾄﾞ形式かよ！
ﾒﾓ帳！ 早く ﾒﾓ帳！
A password, in this day and age?!
Notepad! Hurry and get a notepad!
Putsun.
ﾌﾟﾂﾝ…｡
Ack!
(３人)あぁっ！
(神楽)ﾎﾝﾄに消えちゃったよ｡
She turned herself off!
ﾊﾟｽﾜｰﾄﾞ なんて言ってました？
くさりまぐろが なんたら…｡
What did she say her password was?
Kusarimaguro something or other...
Why is there no save function when the adventure turns off?
つうか なんで 冒険の書が
消えたっつってんのに➡
ｾｰﾌﾞ機能がねえんだよ！
ｺｲﾂ ﾀﾇｷ寝入り こいてるぜ｡
She's faking it. She just doesn't want to do any work.
働きたくねえだけだよ｡
おい 起きろ ﾎﾞｹ！
Hey! Wake up, dummy!
Stop sleeping, you rotten tuna! You deserve to get shot 16 times, dummy!
寝てんじゃねえよ 腐れﾏｸﾞﾛ！
16連射だ ﾎﾞｹ！
Hey! She spat oil on her master!
おい!! ご主人様に向かって
ｵｲﾙ 吐いたぞ！
Who do you think you are?!
ﾃﾒｴ 何様のつもりだ ｺﾗ！
Please do not touch the controller and power button during a save.
ｾｰﾌﾞ中は ｺﾝﾄﾛｰﾗｰ および
電源ﾎﾞﾀﾝに触らないでください｡
It may cause damage.
故障の原因になります｡
お前 ｾｰﾌﾞ機能 ねえんだろうが！
You don't have a save function!
I will repeat the restart chant.
もう一度 復活の呪文を言います｡
Hey! It doesn't want to be restarted!
おい!! 復活させねえつもりだよ！
なんか
変な古代文字 使い出したよ！
She's using some strange ancient characters!
Putsun.
ﾌﾟﾂﾝ…｡
待て おい！
Wait! Hey!
いいかげんにしろよ ﾃﾒｴ！
壊れてるｱﾙな 完全に｡
Cut that out, you!
She's totally busted.
You just need to blow into the cartridge.
１回 ｶｾｯﾄ抜いて ﾎｺﾘ取れ｡ ﾌｰｯて｡
ﾌｰｯ！ ﾌｰｯ！
The adventure never got far, so what we have to do is start from the beginning.
そもそも たいして
冒険 進めてねえんだから➡
最初から やりゃいいんだ｡
面倒だが 気長にやろうや｡
It'll be troublesome, but let's be patient.
ﾊﾟﾗﾗﾗｯﾊﾟｯﾊﾟｰ！ 卵は ﾚﾍﾞﾙが上がった｡
Parararappappaa!
Tama has gone up a level.
[Note: Level up sound from Dragon Quest game.]
I don't know what's going on, but she's gone up a level!
なんか知らんけど
ﾚﾍﾞﾙが上がりましたよ｡
Strength: up 3. Speed: up 2. Lassitude: up 5.
力が ３ 上がった｡
速さが ２ 上がった｡
だるさが ５ 上がった｡
気だるさが ６ 上がった｡
Lethargy: up 6. Exhaustion: up 7. I am feeling empty.
(芙蓉)疲れが ７ 上がった｡
虚無感を覚えた｡
ちょっと！ どんどん
負のﾊﾟﾗﾒｰﾀｰが上がってますよ！
Just a minute! Our chances of losing are rising!
けだるさが に あがった
ずぼろろ くされまぐろばろみ｡
Lethargy rising 2...zuborokusaremagurobaromi...
She forced herself into the restart chant!
ﾑﾘやり 復活の呪文に移行したよ｡
なんかだるい はたらきたくない｡
I feel weak. I don't want to move. It's difficult to work.
しごとがつらい｡
途中から ただの愚痴だよ！
Along the way, it's become nothing but gripes!
Putsun.
ﾌﾟﾂﾝ…｡
はぁ… ﾀﾞﾒだ こりゃ｡
This is hopeless. Doesn't look like she'll make us any money at all.
一銭の金にもならなそうだ｡
(ｱﾅｳﾝｻｰ)現場の結野ｱﾅ 結野ｱﾅ！
Announcer Ketsuno, are you there at the scene? Ketsuno? Ana?
Yes, this is Ketsuno...Ana, at the scene.
(結野)はい 現場の結野です｡
あっ！ 結野ｱﾅ 復帰したんだ｡
I'm reporting from in front of the Hayashi Research Institute, where the incident occurred.
It's Announcer Ketsuno. She's back.
ｹｯ！ 出戻りが｡
あれ!?
Tsk, like a boomerang.
Huh?
The murdered victim, Dr. Ryuzan Hayashi, was known as an authority on automatons.
これ 卵さんを
制作した研究所ですよ！
That's the lab that created Tama-san.
(結野)最近 人気を博していた
からくり家政婦 悦子ちゃんの➡
He was the developer of the robot maid, Etsuko-chan.
[Murdered: Dr. Ryuzan Hayashi]
開発者でもありました｡
えっ!? これ…！
That's...
Based on eyewitness reports, the Magistrate's Office is...
(結野)奉行所では
目撃者の情報を参考に➡
searching for Fuyo No. i-Zero, an automaton that worked as the doctor's assistant, on suspicion of murder.
博士の助手を務めていた
からくり人形➡
芙蓉 伊ｰ零號 試作機を
博士殺害の嫌疑で捜索しています｡
At the present time, Fuyo No. i-Zero is a fugitive.
現在 芙蓉 零號機は逃亡中です｡
Eyewitnesses should contact the Magistrate's Office immediately. I repeat...
目撃した方は すぐに
奉行所にご一報ください｡
Could this be...?
これって まさか… 卵さん!?
Tama-san?!
There's no mistake! The robot that's suspected of murder...
間違いないですよ！
この殺人の容疑をかけられてる➡
からくりって この卵さんですよ！
首だけになってるけど…｡
is our Tama-san! Though she's only a head now.
And this Dr. Hayashi-he's the man who built Tama-san and the other robot maids!
しかも この林博士って
卵さんたち からくり家政婦を➡
作った人ですよね!?
She killed the parent who gave her life...and showed up here?
自分の生みの親 殺して
ここに逃げてきた…？
って… んなわけ あるか！
That can't be!
こんなﾎﾟﾝｺﾂが 殺人事件なんて➡
This piece of junk could never do something as mysterious as being involved in a murder case!
そんなﾐｽﾃﾘｱｽな真似
できるわけねえだろ！
We're talking about a robot!
ｺｲﾂぁ からくりだぜ｡
同じ顔のﾔﾂだって いんだろう｡
There are others that have the same face.
だいたい 首しかねえってのに
どうやって 殺人なんて…｡
She's only a head-how could she commit murder?!
There is the possibility that I was destroyed by someone while on the run and became just a head.
(芙蓉)逃亡中に 何者かに破壊され
首だけになった可能性があります｡
残念ながら 首ひとつになる前の
記憶の大半は消失しましたが➡
Unfortunately, I have lost most of my memory of what happened before I became just a head.
However, I am the No. i-Zero model.
伊ｰ零號という型番は
私のそれと同じです｡
She restarted without the restart chant.
復活の呪文なしで復活した｡
Forgive me after earlier. I had an initialization issue. I am now restored.
(芙蓉)先ほどは
申し訳ございません｡
初期不良を起こしていたようです｡
今 回復しました｡
で いろいろ 理屈ごねてたが
ようするに ｵﾒｴは➡
You talked a lot of chop-logic, but in essence,
what you're trying to say is, that you're the murderer?
自分が犯人だって言いたいのか？
いいえ 記憶がありませんので➡
No. I do not have any recollection, so I am simply stating my opinion based on the data.
私のﾃﾞｰﾀに基づいた意見を
述べたまでです｡
I'm asking you: did you kill him, or did you not?
ｵﾚは やったのか
やってねえのか 聞いてんだよ｡
If you don't know, then check your data further.
わからねえなら
もっと ﾃﾞｰﾀ探ってみろ｡
You can't find it because you assumed at the start that it wasn't there.
最初から ねえと決めつけて
探すから 見つからねえんだよ｡
It might be closer than you think.
意外と近くにあるもんだよ｡
了解｡ 検索中｡
Understood. Searching.
Tama has checked the data. Of all things, I have found horse shit.
[Note: Spoof of Dragon Quest game.]
卵は ﾃﾞｰﾀを調べた｡
なんと 馬のﾌﾝが見つかった｡
おい！ GEOに
売りとばされてぇのか！
Hey, you want to be sold off to GEO?
[Note: GEO is a Japanese rental video/game store that also buys used games.]
She's not fixed at all. Initialization issues? She's got the mother of all issues!
全然 直ってませんね｡
初期不良っていうか➡
もう ず～っと不良番長ですよ｡
申し訳ありません｡
Forgive me. Is there a mechanical engineer in the vicinity?
この近隣に からくり技師は
いらっしゃいますか？
あぁ!?
Huh?
もしものときのために
予備の記憶領域があるのですが➡
I possess a backup memory area in case of an emergency,
厳重にﾛｯｸされていて…｡
これが 開けられれば➡
but it is tightly secured...
If it can be opened, my memory could be restored.
記憶もよみがえるのですが…｡
なんだか よくわかんねえな｡
I'm not sure I understand...
For now, we can bring her back to old man Gengai, uh-huh.
とりあえず 源外のｼﾞｼﾞｲのとこに
もう一回 持っていけばいいｱﾙ｡
But...
でも… 記憶取り戻して➡
What if she gets her memory back...and it turns out she's really the killer?
ﾎﾝﾄに殺人 犯してたら
どうするんです？
決めつけてんじゃねえよ｡
まだ わかんねえ…｡
(玄関ﾁｬｲﾑ)
Don't assume that. We don't know that yet.
Excuse me.
すみませ～ん｡
奉行所の者ですが…｡
We're from the Magistrate's Office.
捜査に 協力してもらえますか？
(ﾉｯｸ)
Could we ask your help with an investigation?
We received word from the neighbors that there is a suspicious robot here.
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)こちらに不審な
からくりがあると➡
近所から連絡があったのですが｡
銀さん… 早い！
決めつけんの早い！
Gin-san!
It's too soon! Too soon to assume!
ふざけるな！ このままじゃ
ｵﾚたちまで殺人犯だぞ！
Don't give me that!
At this rate, we'll be murder suspects, too! Let me go! Get rid of her now!
離せ！ 早く捨て…｡
This apparatus carries a curse. You cannot discard it.
[Note: Parody of Dragon Quest game.]
この装備は 呪われています｡
捨てられません｡
捨てられませんじゃねえよ！
Don't tell me I can't discard it! I never recalled getting you in the first place!
お前みたいなもん
装備した覚えねえよ！
To remove this apparatus,
装備を外すには
最寄りの教会に行くか➡
ＡＴＭで 300万円おろして
私に振り込んでください｡
either go to your nearest church or withdraw 3 million yen from an ATM and deposit it to my account.
(銀時たち)どんな呪いの解き方!?
What kind of way is that to lift a curse?!
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)すみませ～ん！
(ﾄﾞｱを叩く音)
Excuse me.
これ以上は怪しまれます！
ﾎﾞｸが応対しますから➡
If we keep this up, they'll become suspicious of us!
I'll deal with them, while you hide her!
その間に隠してください！
(芙蓉)待ってください！
Please wait.
訪問者３名のうち２人
生体反応が感知できません｡
I do not detect life signs...
in two of the three visitors. They are not officials.
彼ら 役人どころか…➡
人間じゃありません｡
They are not even human.
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)もぬけのからです｡
(目黒)感づかれたか｡
There's no one here.
Are they on to us?
Hey! Who were those people?! The house is ruined!
ちょっと！
何なんですか あの人たち!?
家がﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬ！
何回 壊れるんだ ｳﾁの玄関は！
How many times is our foyer going to be destroyed?!
おい どういうつもりだ!?
さっさと ｵﾚの腕から離れやがれ！
Hey, what's the big idea? Let go of my arm already.
お前を追ってきたんだよな あれ！
They came after you. Are you going to get us involved, too? Hey, answer me.
ｵﾚたちまで巻き込むつもりか
こら おい 返事しろ！
…返事がない ただの屍のようだ｡
I have no answer... I am like a mere corpse...
[Note: The response given when speaking to a corpse in Dragon Quest game.]
ｻﾞｵﾘｸ！
(芙蓉)ｲﾀﾀ… 復活しました！
Zaoriku.
[Note: Name of a powerful revival spell in Dragon Quest game.]
Ow, ow, ow! I'm restored. I'm restored.
離れろと言っている！
I'm telling you to let go. You'd curse the hand that repaired you?
修理してやった恩を
仇で返すつもりか？
首だけでは 何もできません｡
I cannot do anything as just a head.
せめて からくり技師の
家まで運んでください｡
Please at least take me to a mechanic.
それに 今は 逃げることに
専念したほうがよろしいかと…｡
And, I think you'd best concentrate on making your escape.
でも 逃げてばかりじゃ
ﾚﾍﾞﾙは上がらないぞ！
But you won't reach a higher level if all you do is run.
それから 武器は
装備することを忘れるな｡
Don't forget to arm yourself. Simply holding me does not mean you're armed.
持っているだけじゃ 装備した
ことにはならないからな｡
外れろ 装備…！
Let go! Apparatus!
銀ちゃん… あれ！
Gin-chan!
There!
な… 何だ ありゃ!?
ﾒｲﾄﾞが とんでもねえ勢いで！
What the hell is that? That maid... What power!
ｷｬﾊﾊﾊ！
見つけましたの ﾎｸﾛﾋﾞｰﾑ！
Found you! Mole Beam!
Time to clean house!
お掃除の時間ですわ！
うわっ ﾊﾟﾝﾂ見える ﾊﾟﾝﾂ見える！
Whoa! I can see her panties! Your panties!
(悲鳴)
Wh-Wha-What?! Monster!
なな… 何だ あの化け物!?
(芙蓉)芙蓉 似ｰ参丸伍號｡
Fuyo No. 2-305.
芙蓉ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄで開発された
最新型からくり家政婦です｡
The newest model robot maid developed by the Fuyo Project.
[Note: "Fuyo" written differently, but pronounced identically, can mean "unnecessary" or "useless."]
家政婦じゃねえよ あれ！
兵器！ 兵器だよ あれ！
That's no maid! That's a weapon! A weapon!
(芙蓉)別名 くりんちゃん｡
A.K.A. Kurin-chan. She's specially designed for cleaning.
清掃能力に特化した からくりで
病的なまでの潔癖症ゆえ➡
She's fastidious to the point of paranoia
購入者から うざいとｸﾚｰﾑが出て
返品された不良品です｡
and is a defective model returned by consumers for being troublesome.
つうか 記憶ないのに なんで
あの子のことだけ憶えてるの!?
You don't have your memory, so why is it you remember things about her?
(芙蓉)現在は 研究所で
清掃班として働いています｡
She currently works at the laboratory as part of the janitorial staff.
私の額のﾎｸﾛを 何度も ｺﾞﾐと
間違えて とろうとするﾊﾞｶです｡
She is an idiot who has tried many times
to remove the mole on my forehead because she mistakes it for rubbish.
She's Mole Beam's bully!
ﾎｸﾛﾋﾞｰﾑの子だ！ 卵さんを
ﾎｸﾛﾋﾞｰﾑとﾊﾞｶにしてたのは➡
She's the girl who teased Tama-san by calling her Mole Beam!
あの子だったんだ！
どうでも… いいわっ！
What...
...ever!
(芙蓉)清掃班は
ｺﾞﾐを処理するだけが➡
Throwing out the trash is not the only job of the janitorial staff.
仕事ではありません｡
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)まあ 汚いﾄﾗｯｸですの！
My, what a filthy truck.
つまり 芙蓉ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄの障害になる
存在を ﾁﾘも残さず消す…➡
In other words,
they eliminate anything that gets in the way of the Fuyo Project, leaving not even a speck of dust behind.
鋼鉄の殺し屋｡
They are steel-cold assassins.
えっ… じゃあ 卵さん➡
What? You mean...
味方に… 研究所に
狙われてるってことですか!?
Tama-san, you're being targeted by your friends...from the laboratory?
どうして… やっぱり
卵さん 博士のこと…！
Why... Are you and the Doctor in...
ぱっつぁんよ もう 今は
んなこと言ってる場合じゃねえ！
'Pachi-san, now's not the time for that.
わかってんな…
このままじゃ ｵﾚたち➡
You do realize...
at this rate, we'll be...
ﾒｲﾄﾞさんに…
冥土に送られるってことだ｡
sent to hell by...
those maids.
M-Maids...
ﾒｲﾄﾞが…！
壮観じゃねえか！
What a spectacular sight.
ﾏﾆｱなら 泣いて喜ぶ絵だろ！
A sight that'd make any fetishist cry tears of joy.
ﾏ… ﾏﾆｱじゃなくても
泣けてきます｡
You don't have to be a fetishist to cry...
ど… どうしましょう!?
(爆発音)
What'll we do?
そのﾎｸﾛﾋﾞｰﾑを
こちらへ渡せばいいんですの！
Hand over Mole Beam to us. We will dispose of her.
私たちで処分しますの！
おとなしく こちらへ引き渡せば
危害は加えませんの！
Hand her over without a struggle!
We will not harm you. This does not concern you.
あなたたちは関係ないですもの！
さんざん関係ない連中
巻き込んどいて そりゃねえよ！
How can you say that when you've already gotten so many people involved!
(神楽)信じられるか ﾎﾞｹ！
渡したら 一斉に来るつもりｱﾙ！
We don't believe you, dummies!
If we hand her over, you'll attack us all at once!
危険です！ もう
私のことは いいですから➡
You're in danger. Never mind me. Do as they say.
彼女たちの言うとおりに
してください！
私を離してください！
お前が離せぇぇ！
Let go of me.
You let go!
ﾎｸﾛﾋﾞｰﾑ あれを
どこにやりましたの？
Mole Beam. Where did you put it?
林博士から あれを奪ったのは
わかっていますの！
We know you stole it from Dr. Hayashi.
何の話ですか うまのふん？
んなわけねえだろ！
What're you talking about? Horse shit?
You know that's not it!
とぼけても ﾑﾀﾞですの！
あれを手に入れるため➡
You can't play dumb. You killed Dr. Hayashi to obtain it.
あなたは 林博士を
手にかけたんですの！
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)芙蓉ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄは あれがあって
初めて 真の成功を得ますの！
The Fuyo Project will only achieve success when we have it.
あなたのような
旧式が持っていても➡
It is meaningless for an old model like you to have it.
何の意味もなさないんですの！
あの方なら きっと
成し遂げてくれるはずですの！
He will make it happen.
そのとき からくりは
神にも等しい存在になりますの！
And then robots will become equal to gods.
何を…？
What're you...!
((林:ああ… 私は
からくりになりたい｡
Oh... I want to become a robot.
(芙蓉)博士 どうして
そんなことを言うんですか？))
Doctor, why do you say such a thing?
《どうして そんなに
苦しそうなんですか？
Why are you suffering so?
どうして そんなに
悲しそうなんですか？
Why are you so sad?
わからない…
私には わからない》
I don't understand. I don't...understand.
[I'm only a robot-I don't understand.]
I'm only a robot-I don't understand.
お前…！
You're...
A robot shedding tears...how is that possible?!
からくりが涙を…
いったい どうなって!?
やはり 持っていたんですの！
You did have it, after all.
からくりが流すことは決してない
その雫… 何よりの証拠ですの｡
A robot could never shed those droplets.
It's proof without a doubt.
渡すんですの 私たちに！
Hand it over! To us!
くっ… ｼﾞｬﾏをやめるんですの！
Stop...
interfering!
Gin-san!
銀さん！
新八 飛べぇ！
Shinpachi! Jump!
♪♪～
新八！ 源外のじいさんの
とこへ連れてけ！
Shinpachi!
Take her to old man Gengai's place! Hurry!
早く！
でも…！
But...!
あとから行くから 早く行け！
I'll join you later!
Get going!
♪♪～
[To be continued]
[Next episode: "Too Many Cuties Can Make You Sick."]
[The maid robot army attacks! Can the Odd Jobs escape?!]
[What is the "Fuyo Project"?! What is the reason for Tama-san's tears?!]